Guide to the Konstantin Kolenda Papers, c. 1950-1990 MS 436
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Konstantin Kolenda papers
c. 1950-1990
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Kolenda, Konstantin, 1923-1991
MS 436
11 Linear Feet (13 boxes)
The majority of this collection consists of Kolenda's own writing (notes, drafts, source material). The next largest group consists of source material only on four philosophers (Peirce, Rorty, Ryle and Wittgenstein). There is a small quantity of Kolenda correspondence, course material, and Will Rice College material, as well as some National Endowment for the Humanities material.
Biographical / Historical
Konstantin Kolenda was born in a small town in eastern Poland on May 17, 1923. When Poland was invaded by Germany, he was taken to Germany to work in an optical factory; later, when Germany was taken by the United States, he became an interpreter for the American troops. He came to Houston from Germany in 1946 under the sponsorship of George Hill, an independent oilman from Houston who he met in Germany.
While in Houston, Kolenda worked for George Hill's company, Houston Oil and Gas, and eventually attended Rice University. Kolenda graduated from Rice with a B.A. in Philosophy and German in 1950, and from Cornell with a Ph.D. in Philosophy in 1953. While at Cornell, he held the Susan Linn Sage Fellowship (1950-1953) and was the recipient of the Graduate Prize in Philosophy in 1953.
In September of 1953 he returned to Rice University and became a professor of philosophy, where he would remain for 38 years. He was honored with the position of Chair of the Philosophy department after 22 years as a professor, and he was also named Carolyn and Fred McManis Professor of Philosophy.
He served as Will Rice Resident Associate from 1951-1962, was a member of the Texas Committee for the Humanities from 1975-1979, and he was also on the editorial advisory board for Philosophical Topics. For the academic year 1959-1960, he was awarded a Fulbright grant and lectured on American philosophy at the University of Heidlberg. He taught as visiting professor at West Point, Colorado College, and the University of Texas. He also received the Outstanding Civilian Service Medal from the Department of the Army in 1984, was named to Who's Who in America, and served as director of the Mellon Workshop in Philosophy and Literature at Rice in 1987. Dr. Kolenda was a very well-known and well-respected professor, and he authored or edited over a dozen books on Philosophy including: Philosophy's Journey, Ethics for the Young, Religion Without God, and Cosmic Religion. Dr. Kolenda died in December 5, 1991 at the age of 68.
Scope and Contents
The majority of this collection consists of Kolenda's own writing (notes, drafts, source material). The next largest group consists of source material only on four philosophers (Peirce, Rorty, Ryle and Wittgenstein). There is a small quantity of Kolenda correspondence, course material, and Will Rice College material, as well as some National Endowment for the Humanities material.
These papers came from Kolenda's Fondren Library study and probably represent projects in progress at the time of his death (Dec. 5, 1991).
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research with the following restriction. Box 4, folder 13 is restricted until January 1, 2054.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Acquisition Information
This collection was a gift donated by Pauline Kolenda in the summer of 1993 and again in February of 1999.
Index Terms
Subjects
Philosophy, Modern; Universities and colleges
- Series I: General writings and office files, 246831
  - Biographical items, 246865 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 246864 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Course exams, 246863 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous, 246862 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Will Rice College, 1957-1970, 246861 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities, 246860 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Religion and the Humanities, 246859 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - NEH Interpretation Institute, 246858 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Kolenda writings: American Philosophy, 246857 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Kolenda writings: Being a Person, 246856 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Kolenda writings: Blessedness, 246855 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Kolenda writings: Concept of Divine Origin, 246854 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Kolenda writings: Ethics for the Young, 246853 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Kolenda writings: Cosmic Religion; an Autobiography of the Universe, 246852 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Kolenda writings: Form of Life, 246851 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Kolenda writings: Freedom of Reason, 246850 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Kolenda writings: Fulton Frestschrift, 246849 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Kolenda writings: Historical Introduction to Philosophy, 246848 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Kolenda writings: Humanities Undefended, 246847 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Kolenda writings: In Defense of Practical Reason, 246846 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Kolenda writings: Logical Conflicts in the Concept of God, 246845 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Kolenda writings: Misc. articles, offprints, reviews, 246844 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Kolenda writings: Philosophy Democratized, 246843 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Kolenda writings: Philosophy in Literature, 246842 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Kolenda writings: Religious Spirit of Humanism, 246841 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Kolenda writings: Religion Without God, 246840 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Kolenda writings: "Rorty's Hermeneutic Roar", 246839 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Kolenda writings: A Socratic Quarter, 246838 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Kolenda writings: "To Be a Person", 246837 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Kolenda writings: "Unconscious Motives and Human Action", 246836 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Background material on Charles Peirce, 246835 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Background material on Charles Peirce, 246834 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Background material on Richard Rorty and Gilbert Ryle, 246833 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Background material on Ludwig Wittgenstein, 246832 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Series II: Correspondence, Business [Office Files], 246723
  - A misc., 246830 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - American Philosophy Conference, 246829 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Aristotelian Society, 246828 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Arnold, Margaret, 246827 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - B misc., 246826 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Bacard, Andre, 246825 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Bergman, "Mom" and "Pop", 246824 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Berry College, 246823 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Bigelow, Karen, 246822 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Boysen, August Henry, Jr., 246821 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Brooker, Jewel, 246820 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - C misc., 246819 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Clancey, Bill, 246818 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - D misc., 246817 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Dallas Morning News, 246816 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Downing, Irene, 246815 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Dubik, Jim, 246814 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Duce, Leonard A., 246813 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - E misc., 246812 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Eudaimonism Conference, 246811 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - F misc., 246810 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Florida Pres, 246809 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Fulton, Street and Edythe, 246808 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - G misc., 246807 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Gray, Glenn, 246806 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Grygar, Margot, 246805 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - H misc., 246804 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Hartle, Anthony E., 246803 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Hecher, Margot, 246802 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Hellenschmidt, Marianne, 246801 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Higgs, Ted, 246800 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Hill, George A. family, 246799 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Houston Philosophical Society, 246798 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Ilaria, Robert L., 246797 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - J misc, 246796 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Jones, Karen, 246795 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - K misc., 246794 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Kegley, Charles and Jacie, 246793 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Kekes, John, 246792 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Krauss, Dietliende, "Didi"", 246791 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Kuhfuss, Johanna, 246790 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Kulsta, Mark, 246789 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - L miscl, 246788 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Linfield College, 246787 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Losowsky coll, 246786 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - M Misc, 246785 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Macmillan Press Ltd., 246784 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Magree, Bryan, 246783 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Malcolm, Norman, 246782 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Maneli, Mieczyslaw, 246781 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Matschat, Elke, 246780 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Matusow, Allen J., 246779 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Medical Humanities Institute, 246778 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Meyer, Gerlad, 246777 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Miller, Nelon, 246776 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Murphy, Arthur E., 246775 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - N misc., 246774 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Newton, Robert, 246773 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Norton, David, 246772 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - O misc., 246771 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Olesnitzky, George, 246770 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Olesnitzky, George, 246769 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Olesnitzky, George, 246768 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Orfield, Olivia Fuller, 246767 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - P misc., 246766 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Pappas, Regina, 246765 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Par, Leatha, 246764 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Peden, Creihton, 246763 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Phi Beta Kappa, 246762 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - "Philosophy for Children", 246761 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Pincoffs, Edmund, 246760 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Professional societies, 246759 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Publications, misc., 246758 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - R misc., 246757 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Rorty, Richard, 246756 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Rupp, George, 246755 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Ryrle, Gilbert, 246754 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - S misc., 246753 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Silber, John, 246752 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Smith, Beth, 246751 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Smith, "Mom", 246750 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Society for the Advancement of American Philosophy, 246749 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Southwestern Philosophical Society, 246748 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Stark, Willa, 246747 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Stark, Willa, 246746 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Starnes, Elisabeth, 246745 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Suckiel, Ellen, 246744 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - T misc., 246743 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Tannous, Afif, 246742 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Texas Committee for the Humanities, 246741 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Tsanoff, Radoslav and Corinne, 246740 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - V misc., 246739 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Vinidakis, Stelios, 246738 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Vlastos, Gregory, 246737 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - W misc., 246736 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Waveland Press, Inc., 246735 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Wheatley High School, 246734 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Worden, Helen, 246733 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Y misc., 246732 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Z misc., 246731 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Zea, Leopold, 246730 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Zeiske, Evelyn, 246729 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Jayne, 246728 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Ann, 246727 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Kathy, 246726 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Misc. – unidentified, 246725 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Misc. – unidentified, 246724 (Box 6, Folder 24)
- Series III: Correspondence - Family, 246712
  - Balle, Pelagia "Linda" Kolenda [sister], 246722 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Balle, Pelagia "Linda" Kolenda [sister], 246721 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Czjkowska family, 246720 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Fox, Betty Jean "BJ", 246719 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Kolenda, Betty Jean Fox, 246718 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Kolenda, Christopher, 246717 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Kolenda, Helena, 246716 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Kolenda, Pauline, 246715 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Roether, Stefan and Almut, 246714 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Family-various, 246713 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Series IV: Personal, 246685
  - Immigration/naturalization papers, 246711 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Passports, 246710 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Business cards/i.d.s, 246709 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Vitae, 246708 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Newsclips, 246707 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Thesis: "Die Welt als Erlebnis", 246706 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Rice University Commencement, 1950, 246705 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Cornell Univ. course papers, 1951-52, 246704 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Cornell Univ. course papers, 1952, 246703 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Fulbright Fellowship, 1959, 246702 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Travel, 246701 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Conferences, 246700 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Award, honors, 246699 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - U.S. Military Academy Awards Covocation, 1991, 246698 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Memorial service and tributes, 246697 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Hill, George A. Jr. newsclips and photos, 246696 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Photographs and sketch, 246695 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Photographs, 246694 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Yearly appointment books, 246693 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Telephone directories, 246692 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Notes, 246691 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - "Old manuscript written at the Victory Guest House, 1945-46", 246690 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Awards, 246689 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Door nameplate, 246688 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Kolenda family history, 246687 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Line etching, "We're Bullish on the War" by Derek Boshier, 246686 (Box 7, Folder 31)
- Series V: Rice-related, 246646
  - Administrative memos, 246684 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Alumni Association, 246683 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - American Participant Program-USIA, 246682 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Author reception, 246681 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Coherent Minor, 246680 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Continuing Studies, 246679 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 246678 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Counseling Center, 246677 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Course evaluations, 246676 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Course evaluations, 246675 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Dean of Humanities search, 1980, 246674 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Departmental corresp., 1970s-80s, 246673 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Departmental corresp., 1980-90s, 246672 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Employment corresp., 246671 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - [Sample] Exams, 246670 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Kant Colloquium, 246669 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Humanities Research Council, 246668 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Lectures, seminars, 246667 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Lovett 307, Master 177, 246666 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Mellon program, 246665 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Philosophy Dept. memos, 246664 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Philosophy Dept., Rice Students and Counter culture, 246663 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Philosophy 102 Meaning of Life, Course packet, 246662 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Philosophy 102 Meaning of Life, course packet, 246661 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Recommendations, 246660 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Reports of the President, 246659 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Rice Annual Fund, 246658 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Rice Circle, 246657 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Rice Speakers Bureau, 246656 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Ryle Symposium, 246655 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Sabbatical, 1973-74, 246654 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Sabbatical, 1990, 246653 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Teaching evaluations, Spring 1975, 246652 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Teaching evaluations, n.d., 246651 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Tsanoff Endowment Fund, 246650 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Tsanoff Festschrift, 246649 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Tsanoff memorials, 246648 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Will Rice College, 246647 (Box 8, Folder 38)
- Series VI: Teaching materials/research, 246587
  - Billy Budd, 246645 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Camus, 246644 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Conrad, Joseph, 246643 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Contemporary Philosophy, 246642 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Dewey, John, 246641 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Don Quixote, 246640 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Dostoyevsky, 246639 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Ethics, 246638 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Ethics-Contemporary, 246637 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - [High School] Ethics, 246636 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - German literature, 246635 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Goethe, 246634 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Greek Philosophy, 246633 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Hamlet, 246632 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Heidegger, 246631 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Humanism, 246630 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Humanities 101, 1988, 246629 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Humanities 101, 1989, 246628 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Introduction to Philosophy, 246627 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - James, William, 246626 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Kant, 246625 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Linfield College presentation, 246624 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Mann, Thomas, 246623 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Marxism, 246622 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Mexican philosophers, 246621 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Middlemarch, 246620 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Moral conflicts, 246619 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Mysticism, 246618 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Nietzsche, 246617 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - 19th century philosophy, 246616 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Peirce, C.S., 246615 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Philosophical "Phollies", 246614 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Philosophy 102-Meaning of Life, 246613 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Philosophy 105-Introduction to Philosophy, 246612 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Philosophy 202B, 246611 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Philosophy 221A, 246610 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Philosophy 222B-Nature of Freedom, 246609 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Philosophy 318-Philosphy in Literature, 246608 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Philosophy self-scheduled exam, 246607 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Philosophy 362B course comments, 1969, 246606 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Philosophy of Religion, 246605 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Plato, 246604 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Political Philosophy, 246603 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Reading lists, 246602 (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Rilke, R.M., 246601 (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Sartre, 246600 (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Scarry, 246599 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Self and Substance, 246598 (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - Speech Acts, 246597 (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Underground Man, 246596 (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - West Point, 246595 (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - West Point, 246594 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - West Point, 246593 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Will Rice 306B – Sports and Society, 246592 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Women's Liberation Movement, 246591 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Teaching notes, cards, disks, 246590 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Reviews, 246589 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Offprints, 246588 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Series VII: Works, 246503
  - Adolescent pregnancy, 246586 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - American Pragmatism: Religion Without Transcendence, 246585 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - An Autobiography of the Universe, 246584 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Avoiding the Fly-Bottle, 246583 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Coercion: When Is It Right?, 246582 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Concensus Ethics, 246581 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Cornel West's Vision for American Philosophy, 246580 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Cosmic Religion, 246579 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Cosmic Religion corresp., 246578 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Crisis of the Self, 246577 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Ethical Relativism, 246576 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Ethical Theories, 246575 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Ethics papers, 246574 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Ethics papers, 246573 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Ethics for the Young, 246572 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Ethics for the Young, 246571 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Ethics for the Young, 246570 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Ethics for the Young corresp., 246569 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Ethics Precede Metaphysics, 246568 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Eudaimonism papers, 246567 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Eudaimonism papers, 246566 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Firstness and Contingency, 246565 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Hermeneutics papers, 246564 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Hermeneutics as Personal Challenge, 246563 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Humanism papers, 246562 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Humanism and Religion papers, 246561 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Humanities and Public Policy papers, 246560 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - In Defense of Practical Reason corresp., 246559 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Is Man a Rational Animal?, 246558 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Language Analysis and the Critique of Ontology, 246557 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Logic-Philosophy of Science, 246556 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - The Lonely Crowd…, 246555 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - The Meaning of Life, 246554 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Miraculous Life, 246553 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Miraculous Life, 246552 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Miraculous Life, 246551 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Miraculous Life, 246550 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Miraculous Life, 246549 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - The Modern Monster-Idol, 246548 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - More About the Meaning of Life, 246547 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Neo-Pragmatism and American Postmodern Culture, 246546 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - On Thinking, 246545 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Organization and Ethical Individualism, 246544 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Organization and Ethical Individualism, 246543 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Organization and Ethical Individualism, 246542 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - The Pathology of Gap-ology, 246541 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - "Philosopher's Column", 246540 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - "Philosopher's Column", 246539 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Philosophy Democratized, 246538 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Philosophy Democratized, 246537 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Philosophy Democratized corresp., 246536 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Philosophy: Mirroring or Shaping?, 246535 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Philosophy's Journey, 246534 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Philosophy's Journey, 246533 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Philosophy's Journey, 246532 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Philosophy's Journey, 246531 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Philosophy's Journey corresp., 246530 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Philosophy papers, 246529 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Philosophy papers, 246528 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Pragmatism, Prudence, and Moraltiy, 246527 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Psychology Papers, 246526 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Recovery of the Human, 246525 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Reflections on Levi-Strauss, 246524 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Reflections on Psychology, 246523 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Religion papers, 246522 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Religion Without God, 246521 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Religion Without God, 246520 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Religion Without God, 246519 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - A Religious Alternative, 246518 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - The Religious Spirit of Humanism, 246517 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - The Religious Spirit of Humanism, 246516 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Schopenhauer papers, 246515 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Searle's Institutional Facts, 246514 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Socratic Quartet, 246513 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Speculative philosophy papers, 246512 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Stealing Thoughts from Poets, 246511 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Teaching Philosophy after Rorty, 246510 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Texan Values, 246509 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - To Be a Person, 246508 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Unconscious Motives, 246507 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - University Life as an End in Itself, 246506 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - The Vienna Circle…, 246505 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Vietnam, 246504 (Box 13, Folder 31)
- Series VIII: Digital content
  - Various letters (Box 10)
  - Various letters (Box 10)
  - Engines of Our Ingenuity radio transcripts (Box 10)